<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
 <title>m. c. de marco</title>
 <link href="http://mcdemarco.net/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://mcdemarco.net/"/>
 <updated>2013-04-29T13:16:42-04:00</updated>
 <id>http://mcdemarco.net</id>
 <author>
   <name>m. c. de marco</name>
 </author>
 
 
 <entry>
   <title>A Week in the Bitcoin Mines</title>
   <link href="http://mcdemarco.net/blog/2013/04/29/a-week-in-the-bitcoin-mines"/>
   <updated>2013-04-29T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://mcdemarco.net/blog/2013/04/29/a-week-in-the-bitcoin-mines</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I decided to try bitcoin mining after hearing a partial explanation that made it sound more  mathematically interesting than &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/Bitcoin/comments/17so2c/explain_bitcoins_like_im_a_mathcs_undergrad/&quot;&gt;it turned out to be&lt;/a&gt;. (The moment of existential disappointment came when I read that the number of bitcoins cannot exceed 21 million.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s plenty of advice out there for the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.businessinsider.com/how-to-mine-bitcoins-2013-3?op=1&quot;&gt;rank newbie&lt;/a&gt; that explains what bitcoins are and how to mine them with just a web browser at sites like &lt;a href=&quot;http://bitcoinplus.com&quot;&gt;BitCoinPlus.com&lt;/a&gt;. My experience with web miners (during some downtime away from the &lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt; mines) was that they don&amp;rsquo;t work now.  I suspect they may have worked back when Java plugins were less hoary and suspect, and bitcoins littered the intertubes like, well, bits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s not quite as much advice for the mere amateur, but I found &lt;a href=&quot;http://startbitcoin.com/&quot;&gt;some&lt;/a&gt;. I downloaded a real &lt;a href=&quot;http://bitcoin.org/en/choose-your-wallet&quot;&gt;bitcoin wallet&lt;/a&gt; for my &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.bitcoin.it/wiki/Getting_started_installing_bitcoin-qt#For_Mac_computers&quot;&gt;Mac&lt;/a&gt; and waited a few days for it to download the &lt;a href=&quot;http://blockchain.info/charts/blocks-size&quot;&gt;full blockchain&lt;/a&gt;.  (I had to make more disk space in the middle of that and it wasn&amp;rsquo;t clear how much of the blockchain Bitcoin-Qt had saved.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since bitcoins are now too rare to mine on your own, you need to find a work crew and divide up your take. I followed the advice and joined &lt;a href=&quot;https://mining.bitcoin.cz/&quot;&gt;Slush&amp;rsquo;s pool&lt;/a&gt;.  Next, I needed a mining program. Unfortunately, my Mac is still on Snow Leopard, and the options were limited. I downloaded RPCminer, a CPU miner, and set it up to work with Slush&amp;rsquo;s pool, despite &lt;a href=&quot;http://maccoinminer.wordpress.com/2011/05/20/rpcminer-for-mac/&quot;&gt;the now outdated instructions&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slush&amp;rsquo;s pool turned out to have just started extra fees for using the standard mining pool work-assignment protocol instead of Slush&amp;rsquo;s new protocol, so I also needed to install &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/slush0/stratum-mining-proxy&quot;&gt;his proxy&lt;/a&gt; to translate between my old client and the new protocol server.  I had all the requirements to build the proxy for Mac, but I still got some errors building it. Nevertheless it built and ran so I ignored the errors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This setup seemed to work, but no bitcoins surfaced from the rocky soil of the intertubes. CPU miners are too slow for mining in general, and especially so on an aging laptop that tends toward heat exhaustion in the summer.  I needed a GPU miner (that is, a miner that uses the computer&amp;rsquo;s graphical chip instead of its regular processors).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the bitcoin forums, there was a link to an old build of a Java-based GPU miner called DiabloMiner. From the (long and messy) thread it was clear that DiabloMiner worked in Snow Leopard, but the link was broken and the newer builds required newer OSes. I hunted high and low for the missing link, but found nothing but ghostly links to the dear departed download.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I tried building the latest Diablo code on Snow Leopard. (This required maven.) It built happily enough, but when I tried to run it, it complained that Apple&amp;rsquo;s version of OpenCL (the driver to run non-graphics  software on your unsuspecting graphics card) was too old. I figured the best solution to that problem was time travel, so I checked out &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Diablo-D3/DiabloMiner/tree/e3071516e9582127ffc1c69b6e321994146ee4ba&quot;&gt;a version of the code from May 1, 2011&lt;/a&gt; and built it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Success at last! My miners mined away happily for an hour or two, producing an infinitesimal fraction of a bitcoin before tragedy struck in the form of a &lt;a href=&quot;https://bitcointalk.org/index.php?topic=1976.msg1856080&quot;&gt;DoS attack on Slush&amp;rsquo;s servers&lt;/a&gt;. But now that I had a rig set up I could switch to another pool, like the fickle &amp;lsquo;49er I&amp;rsquo;d become.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, in my haste I picked a pool, &lt;a href=&quot;http://bitminter.com/&quot;&gt;Bitminter&lt;/a&gt;, that didn&amp;rsquo;t pay out until you&amp;rsquo;d earned at least 0.001 bitcoins. Even with my husband&amp;rsquo;s Mac mini shanghaied into mining for me, it took about a week (and a couple of unexplained work stoppages from both miners) to reach 0.001. On the bright side, Bitminter also does simultaneous &lt;a href=&quot;http://bitminter.com/&quot;&gt;Namecoin&lt;/a&gt; mining&amp;mdash;something Slush still promises on his account setup page but which (the bitcoin forums report) hasn&amp;rsquo;t been supported there for some time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But (of course there was going to be a &lt;em&gt;but&lt;/em&gt;), while namecoins can be mined with no additional effort by my lazy miners, they don&amp;rsquo;t accrue at the same rate as the bitcoins. So cashing out of bitcoins at 0.001 meant leaving about 0.00075 namecoins lingering at Bitminter until the next DoS sends my miners back there. According to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://btc-e.com/exchange/nmc_btc&quot;&gt;Bitcoin Exchange&lt;/a&gt;, my bit of namecoin is currently worth a homeopathic fraction of a bitcoin, so I&amp;rsquo;ll probably leave them lying in the intertube I found them in for quite some time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin mining is about as profitable as fiction writing in that it costs you more in electricity than you will ever earn. The best way to score virtual riches may instead be to get in on the ground floor of another virtual currency like namecoins. I tried out a promising upstart called &lt;a href=&quot;http://litecoin.org/&quot;&gt;Litecoin&lt;/a&gt; which is supposed to level the playing field between amateurs and professional miners to some extent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My efforts were once again hampered by my old OS&amp;mdash;I wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to find a GPU miner for it and had to settle for one CPU miner on the Mac mini. This rig is not ideal, but it&amp;rsquo;s also not the handicap it would be with bitcoins.  I&amp;rsquo;ve already mined 0.065 litecoins (worth about a quarter on the virtual market) with one CPU in the same week or so of time it takes to mine 0.001 bitcoins (worth one thin dime). Now all I need to do is mine and wait for the coming litecoin bubble to inflate.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Crossposting with Drafts</title>
   <link href="http://mcdemarco.net/blog/2013/04/15/crossposting-with-drafts"/>
   <updated>2013-04-15T10:24:16-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://mcdemarco.net/blog/2013/04/15/crossposting-with-drafts</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been wanting crossposting software for a while now.  People I&amp;rsquo;d spotted successfully crossposting either did it manually in a browser or worked for Google (solving the Google+ problem through nepotism?), and Hootsuite only handled a couple of my networks. &lt;a href=&quot;http://streamified.com/&quot;&gt;Streamified&lt;/a&gt; did more but still not all (and is temporarily without an iOS client).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://agiletortoise.com/drafts&quot;&gt;Drafts&lt;/a&gt; does more too, but also lets me do it all&amp;mdash;even save the markdown to Dropbox for later inclusion in my Jekyll blog&amp;mdash;all from my iPad.  This is my first blog post using Drafts, but I&amp;rsquo;ll also edit it later for some other &lt;a href=&quot;/stream/&quot;&gt;streams&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, isn&amp;rsquo;t crossposting evil? The short answer is it&amp;rsquo;s evil when businesses do it for their financial (as opposed to social) purposes, or when trolls do it to rile up one newsgroup with a discussion more appropriate to the source group (or to no place at all). It&amp;rsquo;s also evil when the crossposter is himself largely responsible for the fragmentation of the community (say, an excessive proliferation of mailing lists on the same topic) that he then needs to crosspost across in order to have a discussion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not so evil when the crossposter is innocent of the fragmentation of his community&amp;mdash;say, some of them won&amp;rsquo;t use Facebook and others don&amp;rsquo;t use mailing lists (or any of them are lawyers). In the case where businesses are intentionally using your content to keep people in their own advertisement-filled &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Information_silo&quot;&gt;silo&lt;/a&gt; (Facebook, Google, Twitter, etc.), crossposting is the pro-social option. Bonus points if you also point your siloed readers to an especially pro-social forum (&lt;a href=&quot;http://app.net&quot;&gt;App.net&lt;/a&gt;, Tent, etc.).&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Polaroids</title>
   <link href="http://mcdemarco.net/blog/2013/04/11/polaroids"/>
   <updated>2013-04-11T13:52:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://mcdemarco.net/blog/2013/04/11/polaroids</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve downloaded my Instagram photos using &lt;a href=&quot;http://instaport.me/&quot;&gt;Instaport&lt;/a&gt; and laid them out as &lt;a href=&quot;/stream/instagrams/&quot;&gt;Polaroids&lt;/a&gt;.  The polaroid styling is based on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.zurb.com/playground/css3-polaroids&quot;&gt;Polaroids with CSS3&lt;/a&gt; on Zurb and a similar post by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.paulund.co.uk/create-polaroid-image-with-css&quot;&gt;Paulund&lt;/a&gt;.  I tweaked them a little and added the handwriting font, a Google web font called &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/fonts/specimen/Patrick+Hand+SC&quot;&gt;Patrick Hand SC&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to make your own, you can see and steal my CSS at the bottom of &lt;a href=&quot;/css/base.css&quot;&gt;my main style file&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/fonts/&quot;&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt; has instructions for adding individual web fonts, or you can copy the link to the font from the source of the &lt;a href=&quot;/stream/instagrams/&quot;&gt;Polaroids page&lt;/a&gt;, near the top.  Some grungier details follow; feel free to stop reading now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ended up putting the link list together manually because Jekyll &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll/pull/585&quot;&gt;still doesn&amp;rsquo;t include&lt;/a&gt; basic image gallery or file listing functionality and the plugins I tried didn&amp;rsquo;t work out&amp;mdash;partly because I was unwilling to wipe out my macports directory to satisfy &lt;a href=&quot;http://mxcl.github.io/homebrew/&quot;&gt;homebrew&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s polite and clear but excessive requirements.  I made the thumbnails with ImageMagick, which I happened to have lying around the Mac.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The export from Instagram didn&amp;rsquo;t capture my titles, so I added them manually and titled the untitled photos.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Social Archiving II</title>
   <link href="http://mcdemarco.net/blog/2013/04/09/social-archiving-ii"/>
   <updated>2013-04-09T15:23:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://mcdemarco.net/blog/2013/04/09/social-archiving-ii</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last time I linked to &lt;a href=&quot;/stream/tweets/&quot;&gt;my local twitter archive&lt;/a&gt; but failed to explain how to &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.twitter.com/2012/12/your-twitter-archive.html&quot;&gt;download your own&lt;/a&gt;&amp;mdash;so there you go.  It&amp;rsquo;s much more useful than your Springpad archive; on the other hand, Springpad now has &lt;a href=&quot;http://springpad.com/blog/2013/03/how-to-embed-your-springpad-notebooks-into-your-website-or-blog/&quot;&gt;better embedding&lt;/a&gt;.  You can see my embedded &lt;a href=&quot;/stream/springs/&quot;&gt;notebooks&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;/stream/springs/recipes.html&quot;&gt;recipes&lt;/a&gt; in the spruced up &lt;a href=&quot;/stream/&quot;&gt;social section&lt;/a&gt; of the site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also got rsync working for jekyll thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;http://nathangrigg.net/2012/04/rsyncing-jekyll/&quot;&gt;this wise advice&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;http://nathangrigg.net/&quot;&gt;Nathan Grigg&lt;/a&gt;, so I&amp;rsquo;m declaring the new site officially &lt;em&gt;up&lt;/em&gt;.  However, my hosting service is not so up, so I&amp;rsquo;m waiting until it stabilizes a bit to take down the &lt;a href=&quot;http://mcdemarco.github.com/&quot;&gt;github copy of the site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Antisocial Media</title>
   <link href="http://mcdemarco.net/blog/2013/04/05/antisocial-media"/>
   <updated>2013-04-05T14:06:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://mcdemarco.net/blog/2013/04/05/antisocial-media</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Somewhere on the intertubes I read an article about the demise of Google Reader and the fragmentation of social media.  It was not quite &lt;a href=&quot;http://io9.com/magazines-have-finally-killed-blogs-but-in-a-way-you-461996928&quot;&gt;this io9 article&lt;/a&gt; that I read via a fellow Odyssey graduate, but it was similar in its concern about the siloization of content.  It was also not &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/future-tech-future-market/7b1a7ddb6ffe&quot;&gt;this Medium article&lt;/a&gt;, though they share the same pessimism about the future of the net.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For one thing, it was geekier, in that the author shared my desire to retrieve my own contributions to the vast proliferation of social networking sites and store them somewhere both more central and more secure.  Though I&amp;rsquo;d been thinking about these issues for a while, the mystery article helped to push me over the edge into doing &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt;, however small, about my fragmented web presence.  I&amp;rsquo;d like to give the author credit but, typically, I cannot find the article again.  I didn&amp;rsquo;t star it on Google Reader, I didn&amp;rsquo;t retweet it, I didn&amp;rsquo;t repost it to Tent, I didn&amp;rsquo;t like it on Facebook.  I may have seen it in one of those places, but they&amp;rsquo;re not very searchable even individually, never mind en masse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had high hopes for &lt;a href=&quot;https://tent.io/&quot;&gt;Tent&lt;/a&gt; as a replacement for the anti-social proliferation of social silos, but I think for the moment I may have to settle for &lt;a href=&quot;https://join.app.net/&quot;&gt;App.net&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Social Archiving</title>
   <link href="http://mcdemarco.net/blog/2013/04/04/social-archiving"/>
   <updated>2013-04-04T15:28:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://mcdemarco.net/blog/2013/04/04/social-archiving</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The rest of the static website has now been converted to static website, and I tossed in one social media archive, &lt;a href=&quot;/stream/tweets/&quot;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;, along with a primitive proto-twitter &lt;a href=&quot;/stream/notes/&quot;&gt;noteboard&lt;/a&gt; that I used back in the day.  I&amp;rsquo;m not quite ready to upload it all to my official host, so for now the new website is still hanging out at &lt;a href=&quot;http://mcdemarco.github.com&quot;&gt;github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Jekyll and Left</title>
   <link href="http://mcdemarco.net/blog/2013/04/03/jekyll-and-left"/>
   <updated>2013-04-03T13:28:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://mcdemarco.net/blog/2013/04/03/jekyll-and-left</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://octopress.org/&quot;&gt;Octopress&lt;/a&gt; was repressing me, so I switched to a pure &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll&quot;&gt;jekyll&lt;/a&gt; responsive theme called &lt;a href=&quot;http://zachholman.com/posts/left/&quot;&gt;Left&lt;/a&gt;.  I&amp;rsquo;ve hacked it up a bit with navigation submenus, header rearrangements, and a simpler mobile stylesheet.  The source code is in my &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mcdemarco/left&quot;&gt;github fork&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also managed to import my Drupal database, with some technical difficulties involving base64 and Drupal books that required semi-manual repair.  Most of the static website has also been converted to &amp;hellip; static website.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Octopressing</title>
   <link href="http://mcdemarco.net/blog/2013/03/31/octopressing"/>
   <updated>2013-03-31T17:10:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://mcdemarco.net/blog/2013/03/31/octopressing</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;After several years of neglecting Drupal, I’m trying out something simpler that doesn’t require the database (which also happens to be down). Octopress is a front-end for jekyll, a ruby-based flat-file CMS. I have backups of my missing Drupal installation which I hope to import eventually.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Twee Two</title>
   <link href="http://mcdemarco.net/blog/2012/03/16/twee-two"/>
   <updated>2012-03-16T12:45:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://mcdemarco.net/blog/2012/03/16/twee-two</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I seem to have volunteered for the &lt;a href=&quot;http://gimcrackd.com/etc/src/&quot;&gt;Twine/Twee&lt;/a&gt; revival. (See the &lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.google.com/group/tweecode&quot;&gt;tweecode Google group&lt;/a&gt; for more details.) This means I may have some interactive fiction of my own up soon, so watch this space&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Interview with the Writer</title>
   <link href="http://mcdemarco.net/blog/2011/08/25/interview-with-the-writer"/>
   <updated>2011-08-25T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://mcdemarco.net/blog/2011/08/25/interview-with-the-writer</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I was interviewed virtually by Lila Munro &lt;a href=&quot;http://lilamunro.weebly.com/1/post/2011/08/welcome-mc-demarco.html&quot;&gt;at Realmantic Moments yesterday&lt;/a&gt;.  I apologize for the late notice; I thought the interview was coming out today.  It includes an excerpt from my &lt;em&gt;Paramourtal&lt;/em&gt; story, &amp;ldquo;Sympathy From the Devil.&amp;rdquo;  Three or four other interviews with authors from the anthology are available under &lt;a href=&quot;http://lilamunro.weebly.com/lilas-musings.html&quot;&gt;Lila&amp;rsquo;s Musings&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My characters were interviewed meta-virtually by Sherry Gloag &lt;a href=&quot;http://sherrygloagtheheartofromance.blogspot.com/2011/08/mc-demarco-author-of-sympathy-from.html&quot;&gt;at The Heart of Romance blog last week&lt;/a&gt; while I was busy packing.  I apologize for the even later notice; I thought the interviews were coming out next month, but that turns out to be when the reviews will appear.&lt;!--break--&gt;  You can read more interviews of characters and their authors from the  anthology by clicking on &lt;a href=&quot;http://sherrygloagtheheartofromance.blogspot.com/search/label/Paramourtal&quot;&gt;Sherry&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Paramourtal&lt;/em&gt; label&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The First Million Words are the Hardest</title>
   <link href="http://mcdemarco.net/blog/2011/07/03/the-first-million-words-are-the-hardest"/>
   <updated>2011-07-03T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://mcdemarco.net/blog/2011/07/03/the-first-million-words-are-the-hardest</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As part of being back on the wagon, I wrote a new story this week and submitted it to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.writersofthefuture.com/&quot;&gt;Writers of the Future&lt;/a&gt;&amp;mdash;-at 11:50pm Thursday night, thanks to their new online submissions policy.  Today I finally got around to logging it and my NaNoWriMo novel in my giant writing spreadsheet, and I noticed that I&amp;rsquo;d gone over the million word mark back on November 30th.  Since I started writing in the summer of 2001, I also managed to do the whole thing in just under 10 years.  (For the significance of these numbers, see my post on &lt;a href=&quot;/node/259&quot;&gt;10 Years or 1,000,000 Words&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t say that this week&amp;rsquo;s story was my best work or that it subtly displayed every one of my million words of practice, but I did bang it out surprisingly quickly; it only took one evening (Wednesday) out of my active social schedule.  It&amp;rsquo;s also my third story in that particular universe, so I think once it&amp;rsquo;s been rejected a few times I might package it up with the other two for sale.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The Self-Publishing Tipping Point</title>
   <link href="http://mcdemarco.net/blog/2011/04/13/the-self-publishing-tipping-point"/>
   <updated>2011-04-13T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://mcdemarco.net/blog/2011/04/13/the-self-publishing-tipping-point</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I found my way from &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/#!/DeanWesleySmith&quot;&gt;Dean Wesley Smith&amp;rsquo;s twitter feed&lt;/a&gt; to L. M. May&amp;rsquo;s posts on &lt;a href=&quot;http://lmmay.com/2011/04/03/fiction-writers-and-learned-helplessness/&quot;&gt;learned helplessness&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://lmmay.com/2011/03/21/barry-eisler-turned-down-500000-deal-to-indie-publish/&quot;&gt;Barry Eisler going indie&lt;/a&gt;.  I read Barry Eisler&amp;rsquo;s long &lt;a href=&quot;http://barryeisler.blogspot.com/2011/03/ebooks-and-self-publishing-conversation.html&quot;&gt;two&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://barryeisler.blogspot.com/2011/04/ebooks-and-self-publishing-part-2.html&quot;&gt;part&lt;/a&gt; dialogue with Joe Konrath about self-publishing.  Dean has since posted some more self-publishing advice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By chance I also found &lt;a href=&quot;http://daviddfriedman.blogspot.com/2011/03/how-to-eliminate-publishing-industry.html&quot;&gt;a very short post by David Friedman&lt;/a&gt; about how little need for the publishing industry remains after the advent of ebooks&amp;mdash;-a reprise of a three-year-old post whose time has now come.  Also by chance, I just got my first royalty payment for &lt;em&gt;Paramourtal&lt;/em&gt; last week, and my mother(!) got a Kindle at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It all added up for me to a tipping point for self-publishing.  It&amp;rsquo;s no longer the crazy aunt of publishing options; now it&amp;rsquo;s the best practice (to pick a painful phrase from the wealth of jargon I&amp;rsquo;ve been hearing at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bio-itworldexpo.com/Bio-It_Expo_Content.aspx?id=102622&quot;&gt;BioIT World conference&lt;/a&gt; in Boston this week).  I no longer picture myself submitting short stories and (future) novels to sink in the slush swamps of traditional publishers on the side while I keep my day job; instead I see myself publishing my own books and (possibly) making decent money at it.  I find my new vision of the future much more inspiring&amp;mdash;-thus my resolve to get back on the wagon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s a lot to read into one PayPal payment and a few blog posts, but it&amp;rsquo;s more a matter of intuition than of deduction.  Where else can the industry go at this point?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An update via &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/#!/DeanWesleySmith/status/58427999455940608&quot;&gt;Dean&lt;/a&gt;:  &lt;a href=&quot;http://tech.fortune.cnn.com/2011/04/13/why-barnes-noble-should-go-from-bookstore-to-nookstore/&quot;&gt;CNNMoney reports on the tipping point at B&amp;amp;N&lt;/a&gt;, including the words &amp;ldquo;tipping point&amp;rdquo; and the prediction that &amp;ldquo;ebooks will dominate sales within the next 24 months.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Back on the Wagon</title>
   <link href="http://mcdemarco.net/blog/2011/04/10/back-on-the-wagon"/>
   <updated>2011-04-10T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://mcdemarco.net/blog/2011/04/10/back-on-the-wagon</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.brandeis.edu/gps/programscourses/programs/listings/17.html&quot;&gt;School&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; out, probably for summer, and I&amp;rsquo;ve been inspired to blog again by the recent flurry of &lt;a href=&quot;http://lmmay.com/2011/03/21/barry-eisler-turned-down-500000-deal-to-indie-publish/&quot;&gt;posts on self-publishing&lt;/a&gt;.  But when I logged in after all these months since NaNoWriMo, Drupal distracted me from my intended topic by telling me I&amp;rsquo;ve been a member of my website for over six years.  It&amp;rsquo;s been about that long since I sold &lt;a href=&quot;http://mcdemarco.net/node/76&quot;&gt;my first story&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I had to go dig up my &lt;a href=&quot;/node/1&quot;&gt;first post&lt;/a&gt; about Bloxsom and &lt;a href=&quot;/node/81&quot;&gt;my other first post&lt;/a&gt; about converting my blog from Bloxsom to Drupal (and from a linkblog to a real blog).  That, of course, reminded me how I really need to upgrade Drupal, and what a nightmare that always is.  I also need to update &lt;a href=&quot;/sffms/&quot;&gt;SFFMS&lt;/a&gt; and, you know, &lt;em&gt;write&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Making a list is the first step&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The Finish Line</title>
   <link href="http://mcdemarco.net/blog/2010/11/30/the-finish-line"/>
   <updated>2010-11-30T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://mcdemarco.net/blog/2010/11/30/the-finish-line</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I hesitate to call it a novel, but I have limped over the finish line with about 50,100 words.  In NaNoWriMo terms I think I blew a knee this time.  I did not hit my all-time high daily word count (8,000 or so, I think) but I did do a couple of days of 6,666 words at the last minute.  Maybe next year I&amp;rsquo;ll pace myself better.&lt;!--break--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the evidence:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/files/pictures/nano_10_winner_120x90-3.png&quot; alt=&quot;NaNoWriMo 2010 Winner&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Paramourtal Reviews</title>
   <link href="http://mcdemarco.net/blog/2010/11/10/paramourtal-reviews"/>
   <updated>2010-11-10T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://mcdemarco.net/blog/2010/11/10/paramourtal-reviews</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A few sites now have reviews of &lt;em&gt;Paramourtal&lt;/em&gt; up.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.paranormalromanceguild.com/booksonreview2010.htm#659830717&quot;&gt;The Paranormal Romance Guild&lt;/a&gt; gives my story (&amp;ldquo;Sympathy From the Devil&amp;rdquo;) 5 stars and calls it a &amp;ldquo;[f]un tale with a funny ending.&amp;rdquo;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://clarahanoux.blogspot.com/search/label/review&quot;&gt;Clara Hanoux&lt;/a&gt; summarizes it as &lt;a href=&quot;http://clarahanoux.blogspot.com/2010/11/review-sympathy-from-devil-by-m-c.html&quot;&gt;&amp;ldquo;cute&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; and says, &amp;ldquo;This might just be the best story of the anthology!&amp;rdquo;&lt;!--break--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Editor Kevin Hosey is collecting reviews at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cliffhangerbooks.com/reviews.html&quot;&gt;the Cliffhanger Books site&lt;/a&gt;, selling merchandise at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cafepress.com/CliffhangerBooks&quot;&gt;CafePress&lt;/a&gt;, and also planning a book signing in Dallas on January 22nd.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 
</feed>
